Okay, this section may feel like it's a
bunch of different things jammed
together. So, this video is to kind of
help tie together all the things that
we're going to be talking about. When
you do software development, uh, full
stack development, when you are
programming, um, oftentimes you will
find yourself using libraries and
functions that other people wrote. Um,
and this is going to cover several of
those. Um, some of them are going to
cover libraries that you have to bring
into your code, and others are going to
cover libraries that are pre-built into
the browser that you can just go ahead
and access. Um, but why do we like
libraries? Well, because libraries make
it faster to develop our code. If you
have a problem, um, chances are someone
else has encountered that problem and
they've probably built a library to make
your life easier. So, for example, we've
already used one of those. Um, getting
data from a server used to be really,
really hard. Um, and you used to have to
do a whole bunch of callbacks nested
together. Then someone came along and
built fetch so that we could take
advantage of promises and it's much
easier to fetch data now because someone
built that. And if you are trying to
securely store passwords, someone built
a library for that. There are a lot of
libraries that make your life easier.
Why do we like libraries? Because they
make our code faster. Um, we can just
use someone else's code and it doesn't
take us as long to build something. The
downside is that if someone upgrades the
library, it might break your code or
they could start charging money to use
the library and then now you're stuck
either paying them or writing it from
scratch. Um, so those are some
trade-offs you have to consider. But in
general, the benefits of using a library
far outweigh the costs of using the